# Julian Leal

Nashville, TN | 518-932-3855 | julianleal1997@gmail.com <u>LinkedIn</u> | <u>Github</u> | <u>Medium</u>

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Experienced in Front End and Back End web development utilizing languages like Javascript and Ruby, with frameworks such as Rails and React. B.S. in Geology. Possess strong skills in problem solving, communication (interpersonal and technical), and the ability to work independently or in a team. Driven by creativity and maintaining intuitive, useful, and creative applications for both users and developers.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Javascript, React, Ruby, Rails, HTML, CSS, SQL, Sinatra, GIS, Blender, OBS

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

## MTG Progression and Drafting Tool - Github

Allows users to draft packs of Magic the Gathering<sup>™</sup>, add them to their collections, and create decks with the cards they have opened. Technologies used: Javascript, React, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS

- Designed a diverse and interactive react front-end to best simulate the desired pack opening and collection management user story
- Synthesized an in-depth database to store several different types of data and relationships
- Interacted with a complex external API to import relevant data
- Styled the application using a combination of custom CSS styled components and Material UI

## Recipe Sharing App - Link | Github

Allows users to peruse the details of, search for, review, and publish their own recipes. Technologies used: Javascript, React, Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS

- Created and seeded database of users, recipes, and reviews to simulate the desired user interactions
- Ruby on Rails to perform full CRUD actions within the database
- Incorporated a multi-layered form input system to handle recipe editing and input
- Styled the application using Material UI

## Dating App - Github Front End | Github Back End

Allows users to create and edit their profile and swipe and match with other accounts. Technologies used: Javascript, React, Ruby, Sinatra, HTML, CSS

- Implemented Ruby and Sinatra to create and seed our own database of users
- Integrated full CRUD actions within the database to facilitate matching users and editing profiles
- Utilized React to provide a diverse and interactive interface for user

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **BMT Designers and Planners**

Geologist

11/2019 - 02/2022

Arlington, VA

- Lead-authored numerous reports within the CERCLA (Superfund) process, including work plans, remedial investigations, and feasibility studies
- Conducted field work including multimedia sampling, Geoprobe operation, contractor oversight, and site remediation
- Prepared cost estimates, project presentations, and interfaced with clients

#### C.T. Male Associates

Latham, NY

12/2017 - 08/2018

Developed, maintained, and sampled monitoring wells

- Logged soil borings and collected soil samples
- Provided contractor oversight

## **EDUCATION**

#### Flatiron School

Field Geologist

Software Engineering Live Program | Full Stack Web Development

05/2022 - 08/2022

University of Maryland, College Park

College Park, Maryland 08/2015 - 07/2019